<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Alex Bajaña personal site</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newborn blog</title>
      <link>/post/newborn-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/newborn-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, Alex here. In the last two years I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to publish a personal blog, where I can upload and share the things I do and think unisg open source tools. For one reason or another, I have postponed that task until today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn3.whatculture.com/images/2017/04/a939825e66db6e6f-600x338.png&#34; alt=&#34;wake&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a blog means a series of challenges that could be overwhelming. However, the R community has proved me once again that no matter how far other users are, their work and participation in the web will always &lt;em&gt;be with you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandemics has make us all change the way we see the world. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen an opportunity to understand the place I have in this crazy world, then I got time to clarify my goals for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want to start a list of persons who have inspired me in this process, maybe it will took a very big first post. So, I will limit to thanks the author of the guide I follow to share with you my first blog: &lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alison Hill&lt;/a&gt;, check her website, really cool stuff is going on there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key word to create your first blog is having &lt;strong&gt;clear the goals you want to achieve with your blog&lt;/strong&gt;. Alison begin her explanation making emphasis in that. I took a good time with my pencil in hand and a blank paper in front of me with no idea was going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.pinimg.com/originals/6c/06/7f/6c067f95ccf0401be464131c4e4f6c32.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;confused_dog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, after I have listed all of my goals and then simplified them in topics, the process had become really smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experience I have found in R, RStudio and Git, the triforce to face the evil. Evil meaning: raw data, non-reproducibility, injustice. I believe in the power of open source tools to manage data in order to use it to change realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://64.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lyfb1zS7h51rnxahao1_500.png&#34; alt=&#34;link\_triforce&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-will-you-find-in-my-blog&#34;&gt;What will you find in my blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;phenomenology-package&#34;&gt;Phenomenology package&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, before the pandemics begun I got the luck to be part of the of the Building Tidy Tools workshop given by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cwick.co.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Charlotte Wickham&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://hadley.nz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hadley Wickham&lt;/a&gt; as part of the &lt;strong&gt;rstudio::conf2020&lt;/strong&gt;. Best experience ever¡¡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I been working in my own package called &lt;code&gt;phenomenology&lt;/code&gt;, wich main goal is to develope tools for economic and social analysis. It contains functions that allow you to make a simple &lt;strong&gt;Demand and Supply&lt;/strong&gt; analysis and, &lt;strong&gt;intertemporal choices given uncertainty&lt;/strong&gt;. Please be welcome to check the development version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;remotes::install_github(&amp;quot;AlexB4891/phenomenology&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow me in the further process of development until it reaches the CRAN. I will share some key tips for you to start your own package. My next blog is an example of use mine. Wait for news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;future-courses&#34;&gt;Future courses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to teach all the knowledge I got from teachers, partners and, again, the great R community. I have some experience given courses of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R for academic documents edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of web applications with shiny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R for enterprises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for create certified courses that allows my students to use R in their daily labors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-revolution-of-open-source&#34;&gt;The revolution of open source&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog will not be about R in a 100%. Since technology changes over and over, I will keep track of the most recent open source languages: &lt;strong&gt;python&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;julia&lt;/strong&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t mistake me, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to compare them and at the end of the day tell you which is better. Instead, we will explore their potentials and why not combine them to create the ultimate weapon against evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;however-happens-in-my-mind&#34;&gt;However happens in my mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love science fiction, gaming and discussion. Whenever I feel I want to share with you anything please consider this a space to create a conversation. No one ever had the truth, no one ever will. But together we can face the difference and amplify or knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-lines&#34;&gt;Ending lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is it for my first blog. I be to hear about you in the contact box. If you decide to download my package I will be looking for any issue and commentary in my repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until the next time¡¡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/fFMWvF3mbzE/hqdefault.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dangerous&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
